hey bre here quick video on Single Leg
rdls because I I think this is very
challenging for a lot of people and uh
and it just takes practice if you do
this every day for a few months in your
warm-ups it's going to become very you
know you're going to become very
coordinated at this movement but there's
some things you need to know I watch a
lot of people do single leg 's and uh
they're also Mike Will calls them one
leg as L deals one leg straight like
dead but biggest problems people
hyperextending their neck which I
struggle with because I've done that my
whole life i' I've looked up when I
deadlift and it's hard to get used to
looking down or packing the neck um
another problem is rounding the spine
another problem is you know coming
forward too much and not sitting back
and then not keeping this leg locked
into position so I'll go over each of
these all right so f teaching a double
leg
RDL you know you teach people how to sit
back and touch their butt against a wall
say here's a wall you want them to sit
back and touch their butt against the
wall well the single leg AR is the same
exact principle you know I am sitting
back with this I'm not going to initiate
by bending forward I'm going to move the
hips back so you need to do that and
then and then uh in line with that is
you you want this leg locked into
position the rear leg stays in line with
the Torso the whole time um so if I come
down on this
movement you know this leg does not it's
not like this it's not like this it
stays in line with the Torso so if you
kind of squeeze that rear
glute it just stays with it so squeeze
this rear glute and then this just
becomes automatic it you it moves with
your torso and it stays in proper lining
the whole time so squeeze the glute of
the rear leg leg that's moving up and
then practice sitting back you want to
get a stretch in the in the leg that
you're working the the grounded leg you
want to get a stretch in the hamstrings
just like you would in a regular RDL so
um to go over this
again all right I lock this glue now I
actually when I do this my hip actually
my my hip externally rotates a little
bit I don't see any problem with that um
but lock it into extension sit back come
down I'm looking down I'm not looking up
and then come back up so this becomes
natural over time and you're
just again practice makes perfect once
you get the habit of doing it with body
weight start adding load I like uh the
contralateral load where if I'm working
if I'm standing on my left leg I'm going
to hold weight in my right hand and then
you can hold on to two different
dumbbells or kle bells and then finally
a barbell I saw a guy named Max shank
doing 315 lbs perfect he wasn't swaying
he wasn't moving just coming down and up
sitting back back leg was in position I
was really impressed because I'm very
good with just body weight with this
movement but when I start going heavier
when I start using you know 27 lb and
above that's where I'm feel kind of all
over the place but again this is a
movement that I think everyone should be
good at because in sports you have to
know how to sit back you know the
athletic position you have to learn how
to load up your hips you can't just Bend
forward at the knee joint you need to be
coordinated and uh this is an excellent
movement to include in in your warm-ups
every single day to to teach you how to
do that